Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Walter Tandy Murch papers
1880-1970
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Murch, Walter Tandy
8.2 linear feet
The papers of New York City still life painter and art instructor Walter Tandy Murch date from 1880-1970 and measure 8.2 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials, four diaries, correspondence with colleagues and family members, personal business records, exhibition files, notes and writings, two sketchbooks and additional art work, printed material, and photographs of Murch, family members, and art work.
Provenance
The Walter Tandy Murch papers were donated by the artist's widow, Katharine Scott Murch, in 1969.
Separated Material
In 1967-1968, Murch loaned correspondence, notes, sketchbooks, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs for microfilming on reels N707, N708, N713, and N68/5. This material is not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Walter Tandy Murch (1907-1967) of Toronto, Canada, was a painter and art teacher. His painting were primarily of still life subjects including machine parts, tools, broken dolls, and scientific equipment mingled with fruit, bread and fragments of rock as if seen through frosted glass.
Walter Tandy Murch was born on August 17, 1907, in Toronto, Canada, the son of Clara Louise Tandy and jeweller Walter Murch. Following his studies of architectural drafting and woodworking at the Technical High School in Toronto, he studied at the Ontario College of Art in Toronto with Arthur Lismer from 1924 to 1927. During the following year, Murch studied at the Grand Central School of Art in New York City with Arshile Gorky. From 1927 to 1929, he studied with Von Schlegel and K. H. Miller at the Art Students League. In 1930, Murch married Katharine Louise Scott.
From 1930 to 1933, Murch designed stained glass windows for Montague Castle, Inc., in New York City. Following a lengthy painting trip to Mexico in 1934, Murch returned to New York City and earned a living painting murals, designing department store windows, and creating illustrations for various magazines including Fortune and Scientific American.
Murch had his first solo exhibition at Betty Parsons' Wakefield Gallery in New York in 1941, and for many years Parsons was his principal dealer. Murch became a United States citizen in 1947.
Beginning in the 1950s, Murch taught at Pratt Institute, Columbia University, New York University, and at Boston University, and attended summer sessions at Yaddo and Skowhegan. In 1966, the Rhode Island School of Design organized Murch's first major retrospective.
Murch's work is in the collections of the Barnes Foundation, Brooklyn Museum, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Smithsonian American Art Museum, and the Whitney Museum of American Art.
Walter Tandy Murch died on December 11, 1967 in New York City.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of New York City still life painter and art instructor Walter Tandy Murch date from 1880-1970 and measure 8.2 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials, four diaries, correspondence with colleagues and family members, personal business records, exhibition files, notes and writings, two sketchbooks and additional art work, printed material, and photographs of Murch, family members, and art work.
Biographical material includes registration documents for births, marriages, and naturalization of Murch family members, biographical accounts, resumes, school and award certificates, passports, Selective Service records, and address books.
One diary by Walter Murch and three diaries by Katharine Murch contain sporadic entries briefly describing daily activities.
Correspondence primarily consists of letters exchanged between Murch, art schools and universities, arts organizations, galleries including the Betty Parsons Gallery, miscellaneous companies and publishers that commissioned commercial art work, and students. There are scattered letters from Isabel Bishop, Leonard Bocour, Xavier Gonzales, and Gyorgy Kepes. There is also correspondence with miscellaneous family members and letters to Katharine Scott.
Personal business records include organizational membership records, family legal documents, insurance records, leases, loan and consignment records, contracts and invoices for art work sold by the Betty Parsons Gallery, expense notebooks, and other routine financial documents.
Exhibition files include documentation of miscellaneous exhibitions of Murch's art work and of exhibitions juried and organized by Murch, including the Jean Dubuffet exhibition organized by Murch and retrospectives of Murch's art work at the Rhode island School of Design and at the Brooklyn Museum.
Notes and writings include the funeral register for Murch, miscellaneous address lists, travel notebooks of Murchs' 1934 trip to Mexico, miscellaneous notebooks concerning various art-related topics, classroom lectures and notes, and miscellaneous writings by others.
Art work includes two sketchbooks, drawings and sketches, woodcuts, sketches for "Novel in Woodcut," an oil portrait of a woman, a mock-up for book Notes on the Hound of Heaven, and art work by others including a sketchbook by Murch's son, Walter Scott Murch.
Printed material includes clippings, a copy of a handmade Collegiate School magazine The New Thinker, and exhibition announcements and catalogs. for Murch and others, press releases, prospectuses, reproductions of art work and book jackets designed by Murch, programs, brochures, a book about Pierre Bonnard, and miscellaneous printed material.
Photographs are of Murch, family members, travel, buildings, Murch's studio, Murch with colleagues, And art work by Murch and others. There are also photographs of various resource subjects.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1924-1968 (Box 1, 10; 24 folders)
Series 2: Diaries, 1941-1965 (Box 1; 3 folders)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1880-1969 (Box 1-3, 10; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, 1928-1970 (Box 3-5; 2.9 linear feet)
Series 5: Exhibition Files, 1953-1968 (Box 6; 17 folders)
Series 6: Notes and Writings, 1907-1968 (Box 6-7, 10, OV 11; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Art Work, 1891-1967 (Box 7, 10, OV 11; 33 folders)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1926-1968 (Box 7-8, 10, OV 11; 50 folders)
Series 9: Photographs, 1908-1967 (Box 9-10; 41 folders)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947; Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-; Scott, Katharine; Brooklyn Museum; Rhode Island School of Design
Subjects-Topical:
Art teachers--New York (State)--New York; Artists' studios--Photographs; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, American
Types of Materials:
Awards; Diaries; Drawings; Lecture notes; Notebooks; Notes; Photographs; Resumes; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Woodcuts
Names:
Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988; Bocour, Leonard, 1910-; Gonzalez, Xavier, 1898-1993; Kepes, Gyorgy, 1906-2001; Murch, Katherine; Murch, Walter Scott; Betty Parsons Gallery
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1924-1968, Series 1:; (Box 1, 10; 24 folders)
  Biographical material includes registration certificates documenting the births, marriages, and naturalization of Murch family members, miscellaneous biographical accounts and resumes for Murch, a certificate for Proficiency in Art from the Ontario College of Art, award certificates, passports, Selective Service records, and address books.
  - Certificate of Birth Registration for Walter Tandy Murch, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marriage and Registration Certificates for Walter Tandy Murch and Katharine Louise Scott, 1930-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Record Book from Columbia University Teachers College for Katharine Scott Murch, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Identity Cards, 1943-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Cards, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Naturalization Documents for Walter Tandy Murch and Katharine Scott Murch, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Marriage Registration Certificates for Walter Scott Murch and Muriel A. Slater, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Death Certificate of Walter Tandy Murch, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Copy of Birth Certificate of Louise Tandy Murch (Daughter of Walter Tandy Murch), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Accounts, 1947-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resumes, 1950-1967, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
  - Award Certificates, 1926-1961, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Passport, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Passport, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Selective Service Records, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Address Books, 1935-1966, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
  - Oversized Certificate for Proficiency in Art from the Ontario College of Art and Oversized Certificate for the Art Directors Club Medal, 1926-1953, (from Box 1, Folder 15) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Diaries, 1941-1965, Series 2:; (Box 1; 3 folders)
  Diaries contain sporadic entries briefly describing daily activities.
  - Katharine Murch's Diaries, 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Walter Tandy Murch's Diary, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1880-1969, Series 3:; (Box 1-3, 10; 1.8 linear feet)
  Correspondence primarily consists of letters exchanged with arts organizations, art schools, and universities including Boston University, Columbia University, Detroit Institute of Arts, Pratt Institute, Rhode Island School of Design, Skowhegan School, and Yaddo, and with students in which Murch discusses his activities as art instructor and juror for art exhibitions. Letters exchanged with miscellaneous companies and publishing houses discuss Murch's commercial art work commissioned by them. The exhibition of Murch's fine art work is discussed in letters exchanged with various art galleries including the Betty Parsons Gallery. There are scattered letters from Isabel Bishop, Leonard Bocour, Xavier Gonzales, and Gyorgy Kepes, and correspondence with miscellaneous family members and letters to Katharine Scott from her father Thomas Beckett Scott.
  - Correspondents with Unknown Surnames, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "A" - "B," undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "C," undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "D" - "F," undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "G" - "J," undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "K" - "L," undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "M," undated, (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-43)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "N" - "R," undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "S," undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "T" - "Z," undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1880-1916 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, 1930, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
  - Correspondence, 1931, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1934, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 56-58)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence, 1941, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 63-64)
  - Correspondence, 1942, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 65-66)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1947, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 70-71)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, 1949, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 73-74)
  - Correspondence, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 75-76)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1952, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 78-80)
  - Correspondence, 1953, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 81-82)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1958, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, 1959, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, 1960, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence, 1961, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 12-15)
  - Correspondence, 1962, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
  - Correspondence, 1963, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20-25)
  - Correspondence, 1964, (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 26-33)
  - Correspondence, 1965, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 34-44)
  - Correspondence, 1966, (13 folders) (Box 2, Folder 45-57)
  - Correspondence, (30 folders) (Box 2, Folder 58-87)
  - Correspondence, 1968, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, 1969, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 11-15)
  - Letters to Katharine Scott from Thomas Beckett Scott, 1925-1926, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Oversized Letter from Richard Yarde, undated, (from Box 1, Folder 47) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Personal Business Records, 1928-1970, Series 4:; (Box 3-5; 2.9 linear feet)
  Personal business records include art organization membership records, documents for the estates of Murch's mother-in-law, Mary Macallum Scott, and of Walter Tandy Murch, the will of Katharine Scott Murch, miscellaneous insurance records, leases, loan and consignment records, contracts and invoices for art work sold by the Betty Parsons Gallery, invoices for Murch's commercial art work, notebooks of expenses, bank books, check registers, a small number of cancelled checks, income tax records, and miscellaneous receipts for dues, art supplies, framing, photographic services, shipping, and travel.
  - Legal Records, 1937-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Membership Cards and Dues Book for the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers Union, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Documents for the Estate of Mary Macallum Scott, 1934-1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Documents for the Estate of Walter Tandy Murch, 1967-1968, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 21-25)
  - Katharine Scott Murch's Will, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Insurance Agent George N. Butz, 1940-1966 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - The Travelers Insurance Company, 1931-1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Hospital Insurance, 1935-1939, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1939-1967, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - Mutual Life Assurance Company of Canada, 1940-1970, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - Automobile Insurance, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Federal Insurance Company, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Insurance, 1935-1965 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Leases, 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Leases, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Leases, 1940-1946 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Leases, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Loan and Consignment Records, 1945-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Contracts with Betty Parsons and Lynne Thompson, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Invoices for Work Sold by the Betty Parsons Gallery, 1947-1968, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 44-46)
  - Invoices for Murch's Commercial Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Invoices for Murch's Commercial Art Work, 1928-1952, (27 folders) (Box 3, Folder 48-74)
  - Perkins and Lavaty Invoices for Work Done by Murch, 1950-1963, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 75-84)
  - Notebooks of Expenses, 1929-1932, 1931, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Notebook of Car Records, 1933-1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notebook of Expenses, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Notebook of Expenses, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Notebook of Travel Expenses, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notebook of Expenses, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Notebook of Expenses, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ledger of Expenses, 1939-1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Notes on Household Budget, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Notebook of Expenses, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Notebook of Expenses Connected with Commercial Art Work, 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Notebook of Expenses Connected with Commercial Art Work, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Notebook of General Expenses, 1945-1967, (19 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-32)
  - Savings Bonds Stamp Booklet, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Bank Books, 1933-1966, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Check Register, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Check Registers, 1959-1968, (16 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-16)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1939, 1966-1968, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Income Tax Records, 1936-1968, undated, (17 folders) (Box 5, Folder 20-36)
  - Credit and Charge Cards, 1960-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Receipts for Miscellaneous Dues, 1937-1970 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Receipts for Art Supplies, 1930-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Receipts for Framing, 1941-1960 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Receipts for Photographic Services, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Shipping Receipts, 1949-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Travel Receipts, 1957-1967, undated, (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 43-47)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1941-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 48-49)
- Exhibition Files, 1953-1968, Series 5:; (Box 6; 17 folders)
  Exhibition files include card files of miscellaneous exhibitions of Murch's art work and of exhibitions juried by Murch, a file on the Jean Dubuffet exhibition organized by Murch and, most notably, files concerning retrospectives of Murch's art work at the Rhode Island School of Design and at the Brooklyn Museum.
  - Card File of Miscellaneous Exhibitions of Murch's Art Work, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Card File of Exhibitions Juried by Murch, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jean Dubuffet Exhibition Organized by Murch at Boston University, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition of Murch's Art Work at Dartmouth University, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Murch Retrospective Exhibition at Rhode Island School of Design, 1966-1967, (9 folders) (Box 6, Folder 5-13)
  - Murch Retrospective Exhibition at Brooklyn Museum, 1967-1968, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Notes Concerning Miscellaneous Exhibitions, 1953-1964 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Caption Cards for Murch's Art Work from Unidentified Exhibition, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Notes and Writings, 1907-1968, Series 6:; (Box 6-7, 10, OV 11; 1.5 linear feet)
  Notes and writings include the funeral register for Murch, miscellaneous address lists and card files of addresses, notebooks concerning a trip to Mexico, miscellaneous notebooks concerning various art-related topics, Murch's classroom roll and grade books, files concerning Yaddo, Skowhegan School, and miscellaneous schools and universities, typescripts and lecture notes concerning art-related topics, and miscellaneous writings by others.
  - Funeral Register for Walter Tandy Murch, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Address Lists, 1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Addresses, 1960-1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Card Files of Addresses, 1964-1966, undated, (9 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-31)
  - Card File of Publishers' Addresses, 1930-1932 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Card File of Art Work Executed Between 1948-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
  - Card File Notes on Works by Thomas Hardy, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Notebook Containing Addresses and Reminder Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Notebook 1 Concerning Trip to Mexico, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Notebook 2 Concerning Trip to Mexico, 1934, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
  - Notebook of Names, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Notebook Containing Drawings, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Notebook Containing Annotated Sketches, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Notebook Containing Lists of Publications and Drafts of Letters, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Notebook Containing Drafts of Miscellaneous Manuscripts and Notes on Victor Hugo, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Murch's Classroom Roll and Grade Book from Pratt Institute, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Murch's Classroom Roll and Grade Book from Columbia University, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Classroom Roll Lists, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - File Concerning Yaddo, 1963-1967, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 4-7)
  - File Concerning Skowhegan School, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Notes Concerning Miscellaneous Schools and Universities, 1959-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Typescript of Article for Scientific American, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript Concerning Modern Art, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript Concerning Paul Klee and Chaim Gross, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Typescript "Taking on the Task," undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript "The Adventure of a Dollar Bill," 1917 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Notes, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Poem "Men and Machines," 1930 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript "The Essentials of Design," 1931 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Writings Concerning an Artist's Creativity, 1951-1964, undated, (3 folders) (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 18-20)
  - Typescript Concerning a Painter's Selection of Subjects, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript Concerning the Preparation of an Exhibition, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Transcript of a Speech by Murch, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Lecture Notes for Dartmouth University, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Typescript "Jurying," 1967 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Writings by Others: Notes on Milton's Paradise Lost by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Writings by Others: "A Few Positive Thoughts" by Louise Tandy Murch, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Writings by Others: "Footnotes in Manuscripts" by Katharine S. Murch, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Writings by Others: Nelson W. Cram's Empty Diary, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Writings by Others: "Teaching Brilliant Children" by Callaway, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Writings by Others: "The Image in Non-Objective Art" by Henry Raleigh, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Writings by Others: Poem "The Wall" by Louise Murch, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Writings by Others: Miscellaneous Writings about Murch, 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Writings by Others: "The Eötvös Experiment and Gravitation" by R. H. Dicke, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Writings by Others: "From the hands of Man: A History of the Arts" by Willis J. Wager, 1962-1963, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 35-37)
  - Writings by Others: "The Highlander Maryville Case" Sent by Gyorgy Kepes, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Writings by Others: "New Life by Breathing" by John Gollop, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Others, 1958-1966, undated, (4 folders)(Oversized Material Housed in OV 11) (Box 7, Folder 40-43)
  - Oversized Classroom Roll List from Unidentified School, undated, from Box 7, Folder 3 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Manuscript Concerning Modern Art, undated, from Box 7, Folder 11 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Manuscript Concerning an Artist's Creativity, undated, from Box 7, Folder 20 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized List of Names, undated, from Box 7, Folder 40 (Box 11)
- Art Work, 1891-1967, Series 7:; (Box 7, 10, OV 11; 33 folders)
  Art work includes sketchbooks, drawings, watercolor sketches, designs for woodcuts, woodcuts, sketches for "Novel in Woodcut," an oil portrait, a mock-up for book Notes on the Hound of Heaven, and art work by others.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Sketchbook 2, 1891 (Box 7, Folder 45)